♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you♪
♪Drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind♪
♪Let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
=The First Jasmine=
=Episode 18=
You eat your soup.
You may go.
You have to rewrite.
Let me check.
Luckily, the inside isn't wet.
You go take a seat.
Leave it alone.
You eat your soup.
Is Qingshuang here?
Why?
I'll call her over.
No need.
What plans do you have today?
After writing the letter,
I need to go to Shende Shop.
I'll go with you.
You have the day off again?
I'll go to work in the afternoon.
I haven't even been to your shop.
It's also my business, after all.
I should go take a look.
Your business?
That was my dowry from my mom.
I even gave you all my property.
But I haven't given you mine.
That's rather stingy of you.
Alright.
Even though it's your private asset,
it shouldn't hurt to take a look, right?
I'll have Jin mail them for you.
No need. Qingshuang will handle it.
Qingshuang is quite capable.
At least, she is better
than some troublemaker.
Alright, shall we go
to my shop right now?
I need your help.
Your Highness,
you've gained some weight.
The food must have been delicious.
Perhaps you need to get more exercise.
Hey, please.
Are you afraid?
I'm afraid you might fall.
If you are, I'll slow down.
Look, he's convulsing.
Was he hit by something?
- His mouth is purplish!
- Wake up!
Whose employee is this?
What should we do?
Just moments ago...
A fallen crate hit him in the chest.
Take a look!
His chest is puffed up
like an inflatable bag.
Inflatable bag?
Sir, what should we do?
Is there a physician?
Please step aside.
How did this happen?
Get him to a clinic.
Purple face, breathing fast,
and bulging neck veins.
The fallen crate
crushed his internal organs.
His lung is damaged.
He is in danger now.
Tear open his robe.
Young Lady, how could you
unlace a man's robe on the street?
Exactly!
People are watching.
Quite inappropriate.
Watch your manners!
Hurry!
Press on his ribs!
A knife?
Will this work?
Stabbing him?
He's already in danger.
I've let the air out of his lungs.
He needs to lie flat.
Get him to a clinic quickly.
Otherwise, nobody can save him!
(Shende Shop)
Careful.
They became inseparable.
The accounts are complex.
Can you make sense of them?
Your Highness, do you know
who wrote "Essentials of Mathematics"?
One of your tutors?
Master Chen of Lishan Academy.
Your tutor wrote it, not you!
So, can you read the ledger?
Princess Ding is remarkably intelligent.
Back in the Lishan Academy,
our tutor often said
that Princess Ding was young
but better at accounting
and calculations
than all his senior disciples.
No need to praise me.
You manage so many shops
and take care of many things.
You've worked so hard.
You deserve praise.
You flatter me.
But to be honest,
I'm getting increasingly busy.
I can't handle it alone anymore.
I think it's time to hire some workers.
You decide.
You may go do your things.
No need to stay here.
I'm leaving.
Oh, this is the book you requested.
Thank you.
Any plans after finishing the ledger?
Nothing else.
Come with me
to the prefecture office then.
You're on duty there. Why should I go?
To accompany me.
I refuse. Jingzhao Prefecture is stuffy.
But I came to the shop with you.
I didn't ask you to come.
You came of your own accord.
You...
Master Feng.
Zhuang.
Please come inside.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Your Highness, you didn't
stop by the Qingfeng Mingyue Tower.
Why is that?
Well, I came to my own shop.
Must I report to you?
Your own shop, huh?
Jinbao Shop has been open for six years.
Yet His Highness has never been there.
Times have changed.
Your Highness,
I advise you to be careful.
One moment, someone holds you dear.
The next, they change as they please.
When they favor you,
they praise your genius in trade.
They long to entrust everything to you.
When you lose favor,
they turn their backs on you
and offer it all to others.
I'm so unlucky.
Your Highness, take a look.
What do I hold in my hands?
Nothing at all.
Yes! Completely empty.
So, you must be careful.
Are you done?
Let's go. Time to work.
Okay.
We haven't met for several days.
Let's chat more.
Your Highness,
come to your own shop again.
Your medical skills are impressive.
Thank you for saving the patient.
You two have blood stains.
If you don't mind,
follow me inside for a quick cleaning.
Alright.
Your knife has an unusual form.
Looks like the triangular knives
in the southwest.
Good eye, sir.
Earlier, you seemed calm and composed.
Do you know medicine?
Late autumn last year,
I stayed in a southwestern hamlet
for a month or so.
I learned some methods
from their physician.
So I learned about pneumothorax.
It's not a life-threatening illness.
If the air trapped in the chest
can't get out,
it will suffocate a person alive.
Is the hamlet near the Chishui Valley?
Yes! How do you know?
That place is remote
and sparsely populated.
You've been there?
On business.
When?
Early this spring.
How coincidental.
I just left, and then you arrived.
Did you pass the Qianxing Inn
outside the valley?
Their snake gall liquor
is strong and spicy.
I've been craving that liquor
since leaving.
I stayed two days.
Just as the owner had a baby,
their snake gall liquor is half price.
Are you okay?
When I was there last year,
she hadn't delivered yet.
She had a big belly.
Tell me!
Were the mother and child safe?
Did she have a boy or a girl?
What was the weight?
Both were safe. A baby girl.
You two.
The patient is now out of danger.
His wife came here to care for him.
But his family is poor,
growing melons for a living.
They can't afford to pay you.
His wife is grateful for your kindness.
She brought two homegrown melons
for you two.
Money isn't better than melon!
I'm glad you like it.
Have a try.
But your knife?
I've wiped it. It's clean.
Back in the southwest,
I stumbled into wolves.
I used this very knife
to kill the wolf pack.
And then I still slice meat with it.
People say
unhygienic food makes them sick.
That's nonsense.
The sturdier people become,
the better their lives are.
Turns out a melon cut with your knife
tastes this sweet.
I told you it was sweet!
(Ren'an Clinic)
It's getting late.
Indeed.
I'm leaving.
Don't move or speak.
Since you've been to the Chishui Valley,
you must know
there's an unwritten custom there.
Love at first sight is tested
by a three-day pact.
If you don't get over me
after three days,
come find me at this address.
We met by chance.
I don't even know your name.
I'm Lin Tinglan.
T I N G, L A N.
As for your name,
tell me next time we meet.
(Lakeview Garden)
(Jingzhao Prefecture)
(The Legend of Gallant Knights)
(Tales of Distant Mountains)
You've read them?
The Legend of Gallant Knights,
Tales of Distant Mountains.
I never read romance stories.
Luckily, I brought my books.
Let me see what you've brought.
Notes on the Armillary Sphere,
Commentary on the Taichu Calendar.
You even know this stuff?
I only know a little.
The sun, moon, and stars
follow constant rules,
moving along their natural paths.
For example,
the Seven-Star Alignment is considered
a once-in-a-century event,
but it's just down
to varying orbital cycles,
with unfixed intersection intervals.
Many factors influence this.
The celestial events
like Mars lingering near Antares,
Venus crossing the sky,
and the moon eclipsing the Pleiades,
all can be precisely calculated
to find their best viewing times
and locations.
That's impressive.
Then keep reading.
I'll review official documents.
Your Highness, enjoy your tea.
Are you all right?
I've calculated an intriguing event.
It would happen soon.
Very soon?
Pinpointing it exactly proves tricky.
Do you need my help?
No need.
Are you sure?
You think I can't help, right?
♪Fortunately, the wounds
the world gave me♪
♪Will be romantic in your eyes♪
♪I came alone♪
♪But with you, all is worthwhile♪
♪We've found a place to belong♪
♪Who hasn't come coated in frost♪
♪But that won't stop us
from filling our home with sunlight♪
♪Through heat and cold♪
♪No one disturbs our peace♪
♪Our shadows have overlapped♪
♪In the vast world,
longing only for some moonlight♪
♪Seeking an ordinary life♪
♪To be together side by side♪
♪You tugged at my heartstrings♪
♪Our wonderful times are filled♪
♪With poetic chapters♪
♪From all the world,
we share a cup of tea♪
♪Small as the fragrance of a flower♪
♪To share it with you♪
♪The candlelight is flickered
by the wind♪
♪In spite of the storm♪
♪No matter how small a place♪
♪By each other's faint light♪
♪The rest of our life is clear♪
♪We're wearing simple robes♪
♪With your lingering fragrance♪
Sleep now.
♪A river of longing reflects in my gaze♪
♪Let all worries rest deep inside♪
♪No need to drift again♪
♪Things change, but you're with me♪
♪The world remains peaceful♪
What's wrong?
What's with you?
You've been acting strange.
How so?
You're suddenly so attentive to me.
Was I ever unkind to you?
Li.
Do you still feel lonely
living in the mansion now?
No. Plenty of people
in the mansion, after all.
Why, Your Highness?
You'll never feel lonely?
Yes.
And in the Lishan Academy?
Lishan Academy?
So many people there.
Once I wake up,
I'll spend hours just on meals,
leaving scarce time for rest.
No time for loneliness.
What are you doing?
What's this?
Your Highness,
did you eat anything unusual today?
Just as usual.
Speaking of which,
I tried Mumantou this afternoon.
I found it novel and ate quite a bit.
Any past reactions to it, Your Highness?
Never had it before.
Please don't worry, Your Highness.
In my view, Her Highness suffers
from food intolerance.
The rash now is likely harmless.
How to treat it, then?
Stop consumption, Your Highness.
Don't scratch. Drink lots of water.
Recovery should take days.
Thank you.
(Wen Quan)
The petals are added, Your Highness.
Qingyu, why is the water so hot?
Not hot. I just felt it.
Definitely hot. Feel it again.
It's strange.
How could it be hot?
Fell for it, didn't you?
My dress got wet.
Stop it, Your Highness.
Come on, join my bath.
No! I won't!
(Tranquil)
You can't scratch.
The physician warned against it.
Scratching causes scarring.
But it's itchy.
Qingyu is right.
Scratching leads to a disfigured face.
It's not that serious.
It's just a tiny rash.
You're making such a big fuss about it.
Are you a physician?
Yes, I am.
(Wen Quan)
Come, bask in the sun with me.
Alright.
Mark my words, don't scratch.
Bear with it for now.
It will get better tomorrow.
Don't worry.
Qingshuang will stay with me.
Qingshuang?
Qingshuang will stay with me tonight.
I'm sorry?
I'm staying.
We won't sleep in separate rooms.
Are you serious?
Yes.
Li.
We've been married for some time now.
Before, I was disabled,
and I didn't know how you felt.
But now, those concerns are gone.
Time to consummate our marriage.
Why?
What do you mean?
Now that we're husband and wife,
it's natural to share the same bed,
isn't it?
But it never happened before.
Didn't I just explain why?
Before, I was disabled,
and I didn't know how you felt about me.
What? Are you unwilling?
It's not like that.
In that case, let's go to sleep then.
He's fallen asleep?
Stop scratching it. It's almost healed.
You are unwell today.
Relax. Go to bed.
Come on.
I was about to go to bed,
but I was afraid of waking you up.
Why are you laughing?
Li, were you happy today?
Sure.
I hope that from now on,
you'll always be happy like today.
I will, just like today,
stay with you.
The past is in the past.
Late loved ones can't come back.
But we
have to move on.
Li, you lost your mother,
and I lost my father and brother.
From now on, we'll have each other.
No matter what path you take,
smooth or thorny,
I'll be with you.
You won't be alone anymore.
Stop talking.
Once I'm better,
I want to hear it again.
Go to sleep.
Revenue Clerk Gu has arrested my people
without even a heads-up.
If there isn't a good explanation
for this,
don't blame me for losing my cool.
Military Secretary Wang, calm down!
Revenue Clerk Gu knows what he is doing.
But
if he privately detains an officer
without evidence,
I'll absolutely ask the Prefect
for an explanation
and make it clear to all
that the laws are no joke!
Military Secretary Wang, calm down.
Deputy Prefect Zheng,
the arrest was ordered
by the Prefect himself.
As for the reason,
Qiu Xian, a squad leader,
makes 20 guan a year.
According to the Bureau of Revenue,
he has no inherited property
for three generations,
and it's recorded that way
on Wannian County's household register.
Also, the Bureau checked
his three years of spending records.
No large deposits whatsoever.
His income is small.
He has no inheritance or work.
So, how did he
afford the three-courtyard mansion
in Anye Ward a year ago?
The Prefect noticed
his suspicious activity.
So he ordered Bureau of Revenue
and Bureau of Justice to investigate.
I followed the trail,
tracing back to the chase
for the Red Fox in Penglai Alley.
And sure enough,
he vanished midway for almost an hour.
He didn't return
until the target disappeared.
Several of his squad mates testified
and signed statements,
and we have the camp logbook
and patrol maps from that night
as evidence.
Military Secretary Wang,
isn't it already enough to convince you?
Am I allowed to hold him?
Qiu Xian, be honest.
Any false statements?
Speak! What really happened?
How dare you!
Speak! Where did the money come from?
Who did you meet that night?
If you conceal the truth again,
nobody will save your worthless life.
(Meng's Incense Shop)
(Incense)
By the order of Jingzhao Prefecture,
resisters will be killed without mercy!
Sir, spare me, please!
I'm just an incense seller.
Behave yourself.
Answer whatever you're asked,
and you'll spare yourself the pain.
I really am just an incense seller.
Enough!
Speak! Who ordered you?
Who did you contact? Hand over the list!
Okay! Show mercy, please.
I'll get the list for you now.
Your Highness,
urgent notice from Jingzhao Prefecture.
Your Highness.
Over here.
(Tuisi Pavilion)
The traitor is my subordinate Qiu Xian.
On the day we tried to catch Red Fox,
he went to an incense shop
in West Market to warn them.
We rushed over and captured the steward.
But before we interrogated him,
that steward took his own life.
One more thing.
According to the Revenue Clerk,
he used to work in the Eastern Palace.
The Eastern Palace?
Revenue Clerk Gu looked into it.
His name is Chen Bing.
He was a registrar
of the Catering Bureau.
After the fire at the Eastern Palace
eight years ago, he was exiled.
It was previously heard
that he died midway.
He should have died years ago.
Yet he hid in the capital,
selling incense for eight years.
So Yuan Fang's death seems connected
to the Eastern Palace.
Was Deputy Prefect Zheng also present
at the incense shop?
Yes.
Ten years ago,
he served as Director of Rituals
in the Ministry of Rites
and often dealt with the Eastern Palace.
With his eye for detail,
there's no way
he wouldn't recognize Chen Bing.
Deputy Prefect Zheng is suspicious.
Find out what he did tonight.
Yes.
Go to Prince Li's mansion.
Chen Bing killed himself on the spot.
That's what happened.
So Mo Jingli killed Yuan Fang,
trying to sow discord
between the Empress Dowager and me.
The Emperor seizes the chance
to grab power
when we fight.
What does Mo Jingli want?
Zhao Ting! Mobilize my guards,
to Prince Li's mansion.
Yes!
(Jingsi Palace)
(Your Highness,
live first, no matter what.)
(The Crown Prince died.)
(Marquis Muyang and the Empress Dowager
sent men to set the fire.)
(Live on with hatred.)
Hurry! Move everything out. Hurry!
Your Highness.
Let go of me!
Let go!
Your Highness!
Your Highness! What's happening?
Why is it in such chaos?
Tell me, Your Highness!
Chief Secretary Sui.
Did I not order you
to escort her back to Ye Mansion?
Your Highness, I had people...
I won't go back.
Your Highness. I won't leave.
I want to stay with you.
Tell me, what is really happening?
We can face it together.
I apologize to you.
Listen to me. Go.
If I'm lucky enough,
we might meet again.
Your Highness, I won't leave!
Was it that night?
Send her away.
Let go of me!
Let go!
Your Highness!
I'm not leaving, Your Highness!
Let go!
- Ma'am.
- Get out of here.
No, ma'am.
Be good.
- Ma'am.
- Come on.
I won't leave!
Your Highness,
please listen to His Highness.
Going to Ye Mansion now is the safest.
No. His Highness is definitely
hiding something from me.
Something must have happened.
I can't leave, ma'am.
I must stay.
Your Highness, you must leave now.
Yes, Your Highness.
Fire!
Fire in His Highness's room!
Your Highness!
- Your Highness
- Your Highness!
No! There's fire!
His Highness is still inside!
Your Highness!
Don't go!
Let me go!
- Get away!
- Your Highness!
Your Highness!
The fire is too big.
His Highness is inside!
- Get out of here.
- Let me in!
- No!
- Let go of me.
It's dangerous, Your Highness!
Your Highness!
- Let go!
- Your Highness!
Ma'am, please save him.
Ma'am, you must save him.
Your Highness!
Your Highness, hold your breath!
- Your Highness.
Revenue Clerk Gu,
take men and seal all the exits.
No one in or out.
Yes. Follow me.
Military Secretary Wang,
take men inside and search thoroughly.
Yes. Follow me.
(Prince Li's Mansion)
Marquis Muyang, you're well-informed.
Any rebels destabilizing Dachu
or acting against me
are always unforgivable.
Fire!
What happened? Where is Prince Li?
Find him quickly!
Follow me!
- Yes.
Hurry!
Prefect, according to the servants,
Prince Li took some close aides
and set fire to themselves inside.
Princess Li was overwhelmed and fainted.
Put out the fire!
Question all relevant individuals.
Take the corpses to Jingzhao Prefecture
for verification.
None shall leave without permission.
Yes.
Who would've thought
Prince Li was behind Yuan Fang's murder?
Now that the truth is exposed,
he killed himself out of guilt.
He deserved death.
Marquis Muyang.
Yuan Fang's case involves many parties.
His Majesty has tasked me
with its investigation.
You don't have to interfere.
I'll report to the Emperor
and the Empress Dowager
to catch the remaining survivors
and maintain national stability.
Why did he go out so late at night?
He left in such a hurry.
Your Highness, don't worry.
Maybe His Highness will be back soon.
I've had Xing cook sleepy soup for you.
Please have some, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Qingyu, I saw the sky turning red.
Your Highness, slow down!
Be careful!
Your Highness.
Isn't that Prince Li's mansion?
Your Highness, what happened?
Why are still up?
I saw flames shooting into the sky.
It was from Prince Li's mansion.
What happened?
Last night at the Zi hour,
Prince Li's house was suddenly on fire.
The fire spread fiercely,
burning out of control.
Prince Li has died.
Impossible!
Mo Jingli cannot be dead!
I don't believe
he has just died like that.
Your Highness, are you mistaken?
Li.
His dead body has been taken
to the Jingzhao Prefecture.
(Jingzhao Prefecture)
Based on stature
and the remnants
of clothing and accessories,
the four corpses belong to
Prince Li, Chief Secretary Suixin,
Eunuch Jiang Qingbao,
and one of the guards on duty.
Their faces are badly disfigured.
Greetings, Prefect.
This is the physician in service
at Prince Li's mansion.
He attended to Prince Li's health
and knew his appearance well.
He has finished examining the body.
His Highness had an old scar
on his body.
Though this body
was burnt beyond recognition,
most traces suggest a match.
Any other distinctive features?
I once treated His Highness's teeth.
I extracted his left back molar
for him earlier this year.
The left back molar is missing
from this corpse.
It's him indeed.
(Mo Jingli)
Who'd have thought Prince Li intended
to rebel behind our backs?
Mother.
Sister.
You've heard the news as well?
Yes.
Prince Ding
is investigating Yuan Fang's case.
When it implicated the Eastern Palace,
Mo Jingli set himself on fire.
What do you think?
Eight years ago,
the Eastern Palace pressed you hard,
attempting to get you killed.
If not for your immense fortune,
there would be no peace today.
You showed benevolence,
leaving their child alive
and titling him as a prince.
Yet Mo Jingli harbored an ill ambition.
He failed to appreciate your grace,
even plotted secretly
and committed such a rebellious act.
Such a source of disaster
must be eradicated completely.
Lest it'll endanger the nation.
Both of your share similar opinions.
(Preview)
All connected to Mo Jingli
and Eastern Palace remnants
shall be apprehended.
(Prince Li's Mansion)
The entire capital is heavily searched.
(Jingzhao Prefecture)
Your Highness!
You're finally back!
Something has happened.
Today, even if I kill you,
no one would speak up for you.
Leave her with me.
You can't take her.
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Both joy and grief
make the trip worthwhile♪
♪Trying to catch up
to your own lost shadow♪
♪Within the wilds, echoes thrive♪
♪Clear mind leads to a clear path♪
♪Be grateful to your losses♪
♪Make your steps weightless♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you,
drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind,
let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
♪Unbound by form♪